<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Projects on Ramesh Battu</title>
    <link>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic Projects on Ramesh Battu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study : Self_Driving_Car</title>
      <link>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/case-study-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/case-study-1/</guid>
      <description>This Project demonstrates a real world case study.The aim of this project is to create a model to predict the correct steering angle from the given test image of the road. Here i build a minimal version of self driving car. Here, i have a front camera view. This will transfer input to the computer. Then Deep Learning algorithm in computer predicts the steering angle to avoid all sorts of collisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis  with TSNE Technique on DonorsChoose </title>
      <link>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement:  DonorsChoose.org receives hundreds of thousands of project proposals each year for classroom projects in need of funding. * * Right now, a large number of volunteers is needed to manually screen each submission before it&amp;rsquo;s approved to be posted on the DonorsChoose.org website . Next year, DonorsChoose.org expects to receive close to 500,000 project proposals. As a result, there are three main problems they Need to solve: How to scale current manual processes and resources to screen 500,000 projects so that they can be posted as quickly andefficiently as possible How to increase the consistency of project vetting across different volunteers to improve the experience for teachers How to focus volunteer time on the applications that need the most assistance The goal of the competition is to predict whether or not a DonorsChoose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haberman Cancer Survival dataset</title>
      <link>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rameshbattu.github.io/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>About the data set:  This is an Exploratory Data Analysis on the dataset which contains cases from a study that was conducted between 1958 and 1970 at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Billings Hospital on the survival of patients who had undergone surgery for breast cancer.  Objective:  Based on patients age, Year of Operation , positive Axial Nodes detection and survival status. why the patients are died within 5 years ?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>